Finding Aid for the Norman Cousins Papers LSC.1385
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Additions, 1985
  - Trip folders:, 1983
    - Book and Author luncheon - Tucson, AZ -, December 2, 1983 (Box 960, Folder 4)
    - P.E.N. - Los Angeles - NC cancelled, December 15, 1983 - (Box 960, Folder 5)
    - KCSN radio interview - Northridge -, December 6, 1983 (Box 960, Folder 6)
    - Southern California Permanente - Van Nuys -, December 13, 1983 (Box 960, Folder 7)
    - Wedding of Ved Mehta - New York City -, December 17, 1983 (Box 960, Folder 8)
  - Trip folders:, 1982
    - Laughter and play - Long Beach (Queen Mary) -, November 4, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 9)
    - Tarrytown Group Conference - Tarrytown, New York -, November 6, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 10)
    - New School for Social Research - New York City -, November 8, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 11)
    - ABC/Hearst - (Keedrick) - New York - Waldorf -, November 10, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 12)
    - InterfaithCenter - Wilshire Blvd. Temple - Los Angeles -, November 16, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 13)
    - L.A. County Medical Association - Los Angeles -, November 18, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 14)
    - Concerned Citizens for Peace - Laguna Hills -, November 19, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 15)
    - Cedars-Sinai Grand Rounds - Los Angeles -, December 3, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 16)
    - Chancellor's Conference on Composition - UCLA Faculty Center -, December 4, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 17)
    - SMAG - Dr. Richard Adelson - Washington, D.C. - - cancelled, December 6, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 18)
    - Funding the Prevention of Nuclear War - New York -, December 7, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 19)
    - Saturday Review party - New York -, December 7, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 20)
    - Benefit / ERG / Institute for the Advancement of Health - New York -, December 9, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 21)
    - We can do it - benefit band concert - Arcadia -, December 16, 1982 (Box 960, Folder 22)
  - Trip folders:, 1984
    - UNEX 1984 series - UCLA -, January - March 1984 (Box 960, Folder 23)
    - Morbidity and Mortality conference - VA Wadsworth -, January 6, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 24)
    - Talk to patients and family - Bowyer Clinic -, January 9, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 25)
    - Smith College Alumnae - Los Angeles -, January 10, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 26)
    - Pasadena Public Library - Pasadena -, January 11, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 27)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility - Tucson, AZ -, January 13, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 28)
    - Aesculapians - development meeting - UCLA -, January 19, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 29)
    - Laughter therapy - Hughes Management Club - Calabasas -, February 9, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 30)
    - S.F. Valley of World Federalists - Northridge -, February 11, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 31)
    - Stanford Business School Alumni - Orange County -, January 17, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 32)
    - Pfizer Inc. - Newport -, January 23, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 33)
    - Sharp Memorial Hospital benefit - San Diego -, February 3, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 34)
    - San Bernardino County Medical Society - San Bernardino -, February 7, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 35)
    - Leap into Health day - Beverly Hills -, February 29, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 36)
    - Saint John's Hospital - La Quinta -, March 2 - 3, 1984 (Box 960, Folder 37)
    - Dinner party for T. George Harris - 2644 Eden Pl. -, February 13, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 1)
    - Student Health Advisory Committee - USC -, February 14, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 2)
    - Southern California Counseling Center - Los Angeles -, February 14, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 3)
    - Panel with Marcia Weisman, Dr. Roy - Cedars/Sinai -, February 22, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 4)
    - Family Service of Long Beach - Long Beach -, February 24, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 5)
    - Ruth Mott Board - Phoenix -, February 26 - 28, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 6)
    - Board of Visitors UCLA -, February 28, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 7)
    - Palm Springs Academy of Medicine - Palm, Springs - March 8, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 8)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility - Anaheim -, March 10, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 9)
    - Dinner party - 2644 Eden Pl. -, March 11, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 10)
    - Alpha Omega Alpha - Beverly Hills - - cancelled, March 15, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 11)
    - U.S. - U.S.S.R. Writers Conference - Pepperdine U. -, March 15 - 17, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 12)
    - Immaculate Heart College talk - Claremont -, March 19, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 13)
    - New Haven County Medical Association - New Haven, CT -, March 22, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 14)
    - How soft is soft, how hard is hard? - Johns Hopkins - Baltimore, MD -, March 23, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 15)
    - Christ United Methodist Church - New York -, March 24, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 16)
    - Loma Linda U. Medical Center Staff - Loma Linda -, March 28, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 17)
    - Crystal Cathedral T.V. taping - Garden Grove -, April 1, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 18)
    - Center for a Post-Modernist World - Santa Barbara -, April 3, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 19)
    - Grand Rounds - Charles Drew Medical School - Los Angeles -, April 4, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 20)
    - Santa Monica College - Santa Monica -, April 6, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 21)
    - Love and laughter - U. Minnesota, Edina, MN -, April 7 - 8, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 22)
    - Distinguished Hallmark Lecture - Avila College - Kansas City -, April 9, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 23)
    - Shawnee Mission Medical Center - Kansas City -, April 10, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 24)
    - Congressional members talk - Washington, D.C. -, April 11, 1984 (Box 961, Folder 25)
    - U.S. Dartmouth planning group - Washington, D.C. -, April 12 - 13, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 1)
    - Grand Rounds - Psychiatry - UCLA -, April 20, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 2)
    - Marilyn Wilhelm testimonial dinner - Houston, TX -, April 21, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 3)
    - Health Alliance of Lane County - Eugene, Oregon - - cancelled, April 24, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 4)
    - World Affairs conference - UCLA -, April 25, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 5)
    - Southern California Booksellers - Los Angeles -, April 27, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 6)
    - California Chamber Symphony Society Allegro Ball - Beverly Wilshire -, April 28, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 7)
    - Senior Health and Peer Counseling Center - Riviera Country Club -, April 29, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 8)
    - 1984 National Magazine Awards - Columbia U. -, March 21, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 9)
    - Church State Circle - Thousand Oaks -, May 1, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 10)
    - St. Vincent Medical Center - Los Angeles -, May 2, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 11)
    - Kettering Foundation - trustees meeting - New York City -, May 3 - 4, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 12)
    - Brain Research Institute symposium - Hidden Hills, CA -, Mary 7 - 9, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 13)
    - American Psychiatric Association - Los Angeles -, May 9, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 14)
    - Lasell Junior College graduation - Newton, MA - - cancelled, May 13, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 15)
    - Institute for Advancement of Health - Palo Alto -, May 17, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 16)
    - Pepperdine U. School of Education commencement - Malibu -, May 19, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 17)
    - Biology of Cancer class - UCLA -, May 21, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 18)
    - ABC executives - Palm Springs -, May 20 - 21, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 19)
    - UCLA Extension - Santa Monica - Miramar -, May 30, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 20)
    - University of Santa Clara commencement - Santa Clara -, June 2, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 21)
    - Ruth Mott Fund Board meeting - Flint, MI - -NC cancelled, June 4 - 5, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 22)
    - CHEER - Palm Springs - - cancelled, June 9, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 23)
    - Phi Beta Kappa Award to NC - UCLA -, June 10, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 24)
    - Huntington Memorial Hospital - Pasadena -, June 13, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 25)
    - Children's Hospital - San Francisco -, June 14, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 26)
    - Conference on Press Responsibility - UCLA -, June 18 - 19, 1984 (Box 962, Folder 27)
    - Alternative living for the aging - Beverly Hilton Hotel -, June 21, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 1)
    - Livingston-Wheeler dinner - USIU - San Diego -, May 27, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 2)
    - Concerned Citizens of Idyllwild - Idyllwild, CA -, June 23, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 3)
    - Centinela Hospital Medical Center - Inglewood -, June 27, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 4)
    - Physicians for Social Responsibility - Palo Alto -, July 10, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 5)
    - UCSD students to meet with NC - San Diego -, July 13, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 6)
    - Performers for Hope luncheon - Beverly Hills-, July 14, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 7)
    - Women's Opportunities Center - UC Irvine -, July 21, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 8)
    - International New Thought Alliance - Las Vegas - - cancelled, July 27, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 9)
    - Western Star Trucks - Seattle -, July 27, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 10)
    - Laughter and play - Honolulu - - cancelled, August 17, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 11)
    - Grand Rounds - Family Medicine - UCLA -, August 24, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 12)
    - UCB lecture - Berkeley -, September 11, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 13)
    - Family Therapy Institute of Southern California - Santa Monica -, September 17, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 14)
    - George Konheim installation - Vista Del Mar -, September 17, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 15)
    - Julia Ann Singer Center - Beverly Hills -, September 20, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 16)
    - Pacific Medical Center - San Francisco -, September 21, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 17)
    - A.M. San Francisco - TV show - San Francisco - - cancel[led?], September 21, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 18)
    - New perspectives on stress - Tucson -, September 28, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 19)
    - World Federalists Association - Tucson -, September 28, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 20)
    - Nuclear Weapons Freeze talk - Brentwood -, September 30, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 21)
    - Art of Laughter course (SMCC) - Santa Monica -, October 1, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 22)
    - UCLA Emeriti Association - UCLA -, October 3, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 23)
    - Dinner with Computerland's B. Millard - Oakland -, October 5, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 24)
    - City of Hope - Pasadena -, October 7, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 25)
    - Institute for Advancement of Health - New York -, October 14 - 15, 1984 (Box 963, Folder 26)
    - U.S./Chinese Writers Conference - Beijing -, October 18, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 1)
    - American Bankers Association - New York City -, October 21, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 2)
    - Medicine and Society forum - UCLA -, October 25, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 3)
    - Medicine in the Arts seminar - UCLA -, October 30, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 4)
    - Kettering Foundation Board meeting - Dayton, OH - - cancelled, November 1 - 2, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 5)
    - Mind-body relationship - UCLA Ext. -, November 5, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 6)
    - Zamorano Book Club - USC -, November 7, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 7)
    - Brandeis University luncheon - Beverly Hills -, November 8, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 8)
    - Biological Sciences Association - USC -, November 9, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 9)
    - Sinai Hospital annual meeting - Detroit, MI -, November 12, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 10)
    - Einstein Peace Prize award ceremony - Washington, D.C. -, November 13, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 11)
    - Clinical Social Workers - UCLA -, November 14, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 12)
    - American Speech, Language and Hearing Association - San Francisco -, November 18, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 13)
    - We can do! - Pasadena, CA -, November 19, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 14)
    - First Church of Religious Science - Phoenix -, November 20, 1984 (Box 964, Folder 15)
    - Pacific Coast College Health Association - Tucson -, November 21, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 1)
    - Medical Center Auxiliary - UCLA -, November 26, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 2)
    - So. Illinois University filming - Dallas -, November 30, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 3)
    - UCLA administrators and supervisors - UCLA -, November 27, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 4)
    - Trammell Crow Co. - Dallas -, November 30, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 5)
    - Ask your doctor - Long Beach -, December 4 (?), 1984 (Box 965, Folder 6)
    - Mortimer Adler - 2644 and Malibu -, December 3, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 7)
    - Light up a Christmas tree - Palos Verdes -, December 2, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 8)
    - Evening with NC and Dr. M. Heifitz - Los Angeles -, December 4, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 9)
    - Nucleuar weapons freeze campaign - St. Louis, MO - - cancelled, December 7, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 10)
    - Melanoma Support Group - Cancer Clinic - UCLA -, December 7, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 11)
    - Dr. Robert Ader visits - UCLA -, December 12 - 14, 1984 (Box 965, Folder 12)
  - Address cards
    - NC Christmas cards from (Box 966, Folder 1)
    - "Old diary list," [Christmas card index, returned cards, letter from C. Rajagopalachari] - (in box) (Box 966, Folder 2)
    - Christmas card list (in card box) (Box 967, Folder 1)
    - Address cards, 3 greeting cards (Box 968, Folder 1)
  - Morlion
    - Morlion - [photocopy of manuscript, printed material, curriculum vitae] (Box 968, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Morlion
    - Morlion (Box 968, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Kettering Foundation
    - Kettering Foundation -, 1980 - 1984; [3 folders.] (Box 968, Folder 4-5, Box 969)
  - Travel schedules
    - Travel schedules -, 1957 (Box 969, Folder 2)